# **AYODEJI ADEBAYO**

Hi, I'm a Full Stack Developer with a knack for engineering, modern applications and web services. I am a tech-enthusiast, investment analyst and ardent researcher, with special interest in next-generation digital technologies, fintech and sustainable energy.

10 Silverland Lane Crown Estate, Lekki Phase 2, Lagos.



**a** +(234) 8064180322



interpercelservice@gmail.com



https://github.com/lummy-star



https://ayodeji-portfolio.netlify.app https://ateaseinsurance.netlify.app/

#### **EDUCATION**

## **B.SC. ECONOMICS**

Kwara state University, Kwara state. Nigeria, 2015 (Second Class Hons., Upper Division, 4.19/5.00)

#### **STRENGTHS**

- . Active Listening
- . Critical Thinking
- . Complex Problem Solving
- . Good Team Player
- . Sound Knowledge of Data Structures and Algorithms
- . Fast Self-learner
- . Strong Communication Skills
- . Clean and Quality Code
- . Efficient Time and Task Management

#### LINKEDIN BADGES

#### HTML TEST

Top 30% out of 2.1 million developers worldwide

### **CSS TEST**

Top 15% out of 1.4 million developers worldwide

#### JAVASCRIPT TEST

Top 30% out of 1.2 million developers worldwide

#### **REFERENCES**

Available on Request

#### SOFTWARE SKILLS

Stack: MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js (MERN), SQL, React-Native Experienced with: JavaScript (ES 5/6/7), Typescript, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap5, Styled Components, SCSS, MySQL, Microsoft Office Suite, Figma, Jira, Miro, Trello, GIT/GitHub, Tailwind CSS., Firebase, Netlify, Docker, Kubernettes

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**DEVELOPMENT TEAM MEMBER / AtEase Insurance (Side Hustle Bootcamp** 

November 2021 – February 2022

 Part of software development activities throughout the development cycle, managing tracks of Frontend, Backend, Mobile, WordPress and Database Administration, collaborating with the team lead and other track leads in revising the business plans, strategies, code implementations, setup and managed repositories and teams on GitHub, using Agile Methodology, etc.;

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER / Upwork (Freelance platform)

October 2019 – present

- Oversaw many software development activities for different clients needs ranging from managing tracks of Frontend and Backend development, collaborating with the team lead and other track leads in revising the business plans, strategies, code implementations, setup and managed repositories and teams on GitHub, etc.;
- Implemented redux state management, built and consumed APIs and components:
- Hosted backend API with Docker/Kubernetes, frontend on Netlify using CI/CD.

### **BACKEND DEVELOPMENT / Fiveer)**

August 2020 - Present

- Oversaw all backend development activities, liaising with different teams revising the business plans, strategies, code implementations, etc.:
- Setup the organization, repositories and teams on GitHub;
- Performed extensive automated testing and code refactoring for performance;
- Hosted backend API on Heroku. Revised Frontend (deltajob-ng.netlify.app).

TUTOR (BACKEND DEVELOPMENT) / KodeCamp (March 2022 - Present)

#### PROFESSIONAL TRAININGS / CERTIFICATION

- FullStack Development (ReactJs), Tech4Dev/Microsoft
- Basic and Advanced Backend Development (Node.Js)
- Frontend Development (React JS), SideHustle NG
- Jobberman Soft-Skills Training, Jobberman